Separated by war. Tested by battle. Bound by friendship.
War Horse is a war, history, adventure film directed by Steven Spielberg.
On the brink of the First World War, Albert's beloved horse
Joey is sold to the Cavalry by his father.
Against the backdrop of the Great War, Joey begins an odyssey full of danger,
joy, and sorrow, and he transforms everyone he meets along the way.
Meanwhile, Albert, unable to forget his equine friend, searches the
battlefields of France to find Joey and bring him home.
Albert Narracott, played by Jeremy Irvine.
Ted Narracott, played by Peter Mullan.
Rose Narracott, played by Emily Watson.
Grandfather, played by Niels Arestrup.
Lyons, played by David Thewlis.
Capt. James Nicholls, played by Tom Hiddleston.
War Horse is a 2011 war drama film directed and produced by Steven
Spielberg, from a screenplay written by Lee Hall and Richard Curtis.
It is based on Michael Morpurgo's 1982 novel and its 2007 stage adaptation.
The film features an ensemble cast that includes Peter Mullan, Emily Watson, Niels Arestrup, Jeremy
Irvine (in his feature film debut), David Thewlis, Tom Hiddleston and Benedict Cumberbatch.
Set before and during World War I, its plot follows Joey, a bay Irish Hunter horse raised by English teenager Albert as he is bought by
the British Army, leading him to encounter various people throughout Europe, in the midst of the war and its tragedies.
DreamWorks Pictures acquired the film rights to the novel in December
2009, and Spielberg was announced to direct in May 2010.
Having directed several films set during World War II, it was
his first to tackle the events of World War I.
Shot in England over 63 days, the production used 5,800 extras and 300 horses.
Several longtime Spielberg collaborators—including producer Kathleen Kennedy, cinematographer Janusz Kamiński,
editor Michael Kahn, production designer Rick Carter and composer John Williams—worked on the film.
Produced by DreamWorks and distributed worldwide by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures through the Touchstone Pictures label, War
Horse became a box-office success (earning $177 million on a $70 million budget) and was met with positive reviews.
The film was named one of the ten best films of 2011 by the American Film Institute and the National Board of Review,
and was nominated for six Academy Awards (including Best Picture), two Golden Globes and five BAFTAs.
The film explores themes of world war i, horse, farm life, execution, trapped.